{
    "title": "Time Value of Money",
    "icon": "<svg xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg\" class=\"h-8 w-8\" fill=\"none\" viewBox=\"0 0 24 24\" stroke=\"currentColor\" stroke-width=\"2\"><path stroke-linecap=\"round\" stroke-linejoin=\"round\" d=\"M9 17v-2m3 2v-4m3 4v-6m2 10H7a2 2 0 01-2-2V5a2 2 0 012-2h5.586a1 1 0 01.707.293l5.414 5.414a1 1 0 01.293.707V19a2 2 0 01-2 2z\" /></svg>",
    "sectors": {
        "sector1": {
            "title": "Chapter 2 Questions",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "q_num": 1,
                    "topic": "Compounding",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "One potential benefit from starting to invest early for retirement is that the investor can expect greater benefits from the compounding of interest.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 2,
                    "topic": "PV versus FV",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "If the discount (or interest) rate is positive, the present value of an expected series of payments will always exceed the future value of the same series.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 3,
                    "topic": "PV versus FV",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "Disregarding risk, if money has time value, it is impossible for the present value of a given sum to exceed its future value.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 4,
                    "topic": "Effective annual rate",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "If a bank compounds savings accounts quarterly, the nominal rate will exceed the effective annual rate.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 5,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "The payment made each period on an amortized loan is constant, and it consists of some interest and some principal. The closer we are to the end of the loan's life, the greater the percentage of the payment that will be a repayment of principal.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 6,
                    "topic": "Compounding",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "The greater the number of compounding periods within a year, then (1) the greater the future value of a lump sum investment at Time 0 and (2) the greater the present value of a given lump sum to be received at some future date.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 7,
                    "topic": "Comparative compounding",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "Suppose an investor plans to invest a given sum of money. She can earn an effective annual rate of 5% on Security A, while Security B will provide an effective annual rate of 12%. Within 11 years' time, the compounded value of Security B will be more than twice the compounded value of Security A. (Ignore risk, and assume that compounding occurs annually.)",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 8,
                    "topic": "PV of a sum",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "The present value of a future sum decreases as either the discount rate or the number of periods per year increases.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 9,
                    "topic": "PV of an annuity",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "All other factors held constant, the present value of a given annual annuity decreases as the number of discounting periods per year increases.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 10,
                    "topic": "Effective and nominal rates",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "As a result of compounding, the effective annual rate on a bank deposit (or a loan) is always equal to or greater than the nominal rate on the deposit (or loan).",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 11,
                    "topic": "Periodic and nominal rates",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "If we are given a periodic interest rate, say a monthly rate, we can find the nominal annual rate by multiplying the periodic rate by the number of periods per year.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "True",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 12,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "When a loan is amortized, a relatively high percentage of the payment goes to reduce the outstanding principal in the early years, and the principal repayment's percentage declines in the loan's later years.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 13,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "tf",
                    "question": "Midway through the life of an amortized loan, the percentage of the payment that represents interest is equal to the percentage that represents principal repayment. This is true regardless of the original life of the loan.",
                    "options": ["True", "False"],
                    "answer": "False",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 14,
                    "topic": "Time lines",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "A time line is meaningful only if all cash flows occur annually.",
                        "Time lines are useful for visualizing complex problems prior to doing actual calculations.",
                        "Time lines can be constructed even in situations where some of the cash flows occur annually but others occur quarterly.",
                        "Time lines can be constructed for annuities where the payments occur at either the beginning or the end of periods.",
                        "The cash flows shown on a time line can be in the form of annuity payments, but they can also be uneven amounts."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A time line is meaningful only if all cash flows occur annually.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 15,
                    "topic": "Time lines",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "A time line is not meaningful unless all cash flows occur annually.",
                        "Time lines are useful for visualizing complex problems prior to doing actual calculations.",
                        "Time lines cannot be constructed to deal with situations where some of the cash flows occur annually but others occur quarterly.",
                        "Time lines can only be constructed for annuities where the payments occur at the ends of the periods, i.e., for ordinary annuities.",
                        "Time lines cannot be constructed where some of the payments constitute an annuity but others are unequal and thus are not part of the annuity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Time lines are useful for visualizing complex problems prior to doing actual calculations.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 16,
                    "topic": "Effects of factors on PVs",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are analyzing the value of a potential investment by calculating the sum of the present values of its expected cash flows. Which of the following would lower the calculated value of the investment?",
                    "options": [
                        "The cash flows are in the form of a deferred annuity, and they total to $100,000. You learn that the annuity lasts for only 5 rather than 10 years, hence that each payment is for $20,000 rather than for $10,000.",
                        "The discount rate increases.",
                        "The riskiness of the investments cash flows decreases.",
                        "The total amount of cash flows remains the same, but more of the cash flows are received in the earlier years and less are received in the later years.",
                        "The discount rate decreases."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The discount rate increases.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 17,
                    "topic": "Annuities",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The cash flows for an ordinary (or deferred) annuity all occur at the beginning of the periods.",
                        "If a series of unequal cash flows occurs at regular intervals, such as once a year, then the series is by definition an annuity.",
                        "The cash flows for an annuity due must all occur at the ends of the periods.",
                        "The cash flows for an annuity must all be equal, and they must occur at regular intervals, such as once a year or once a month.",
                        "If some cash flows occur at the beginning of the periods while others occur at the ends, then we have what the textbook defines as a variable annuity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The cash flows for an annuity must all be equal, and they must occur at regular intervals, such as once a year or once a month.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 18,
                    "topic": "Solving for I with uneven cash flows",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "If you have a series of cash flows, all of which are positive, you can solve for I, where the solution value of I causes the PV of the cash flows to equal the cash flow at Time 0.",
                        "If you have a series of cash flows, and CF0 is negative but all of the other CFs are positive, you can solve for I, but only if the sum of the undiscounted cash flows exceeds the cost.",
                        "To solve for I, one must identify the value of I that causes the PV of the positive CFs to equal the absolute value of the PV of the negative CFs. This is, essentially, a trial-and-error procedure that is easy with a computer or financial calculator but quite difficult otherwise.",
                        "If you solve for I and get a negative number, then you must have made a mistake.",
                        "If CF0 is positive and all the other CFs are negative, then you cannot solve for I."
                    ],
                    "answer": "To solve for I, one must identify the value of I that causes the PV of the positive CFs to equal the absolute value of the PV of the negative CFs. This is, essentially, a trial-and-error procedure that is easy with a computer or financial calculator but quite difficult otherwise.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 19,
                    "topic": "Effective annual rate",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following bank accounts has the highest effective annual return?",
                    "options": [
                        "An account that pays 8% nominal interest with monthly compounding.",
                        "An account that pays 8% nominal interest with annual compounding.",
                        "An account that pays 7% nominal interest with daily (365-day) compounding.",
                        "An account that pays 7% nominal interest with monthly compounding.",
                        "An account that pays 8% nominal interest with daily (365-day) compounding."
                    ],
                    "answer": "An account that pays 8% nominal interest with daily (365-day) compounding.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 20,
                    "topic": "Quarterly compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your bank account pays a 6% nominal rate of interest. The interest is compounded quarterly. Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The periodic rate of interest is 1.5% and the effective rate of interest is 3%.",
                        "The periodic rate of interest is 6% and the effective rate of interest is greater than 6%.",
                        "The periodic rate of interest is 1.5% and the effective rate of interest is greater than 6%.",
                        "The periodic rate of interest is 3% and the effective rate of interest is 6%.",
                        "The periodic rate of interest is 6% and the effective rate of interest is also 6%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The periodic rate of interest is 1.5% and the effective rate of interest is greater than 6%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 21,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A $50,000 loan is to be amortized over 7 years, with annual end-of-year payments. Which of these statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The annual payments would be larger if the interest rate were lower.",
                        "If the loan were amortized over 10 years rather than 7 years, and if the interest rate were the same in either case, the first payment would include more dollars of interest under the 7-year amortization plan.",
                        "The proportion of each payment that represents interest as opposed to repayment of principal would be lower if the interest rate were lower.",
                        "The last payment would have a higher proportion of interest than the first payment.",
                        "The proportion of interest versus principal repayment would be the same for each of the 7 payments."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The proportion of each payment that represents interest as opposed to repayment of principal would be lower if the interest rate were lower.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 22,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding a 15-year (180-month) $125,000 fixed-rate mortgage is NOT CORRECT? (Ignore all taxes and transactions costs.)",
                    "options": [
                        "The remaining balance after three years will be $125,000 less the total amount of interest paid during the first 36 months.",
                        "Because it is a fixed-rate mortgage, the monthly loan payments (that include both interest and principal payments) are constant.",
                        "Interest payments on the mortgage will steadily decline over time.",
                        "The proportion of the monthly payment that goes towards repayment of principal will be higher 10 years from now than it will be the first year.",
                        "The outstanding balance gets paid off at a faster rate in the later years of a loans life."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The remaining balance after three years will be $125,000 less the total amount of interest paid during the first 36 months.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 23,
                    "topic": "Amortization",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding a 30-year monthly payment amortized mortgage with a nominal interest rate of 10% is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The monthly payments will decline over time.",
                        "A smaller proportion of the last monthly payment will be interest, and a larger proportion will be principal, than for the first monthly payment.",
                        "The total dollar amount of principal being paid off each month gets smaller as the loan approaches maturity.",
                        "The amount representing interest in the first payment would be higher if the nominal interest rate were 7% rather than 10%.",
                        "Exactly 10% of the first monthly payment represents interest."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A smaller proportion of the last monthly payment will be interest, and a larger proportion will be principal, than for the first monthly payment.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 24,
                    "topic": "Time value concepts",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following investments will have the highest future value at the end of 10 years? Assume that the effective annual rate for all investments is the same.",
                    "options": [
                        "Investment A pays $250 at the beginning of every year for the next 10 years (a total of 10 payments).",
                        "Investment B pays $125 at the end of every 6-month period for the next 10 years (a total of 20 payments).",
                        "Investment C pays $125 at the beginning of every 6-month period for the next 10 years (a total of 20 payments).",
                        "Investment D pays $2,500 at the end of 10 years (a total of one payment).",
                        "Investment E pays $250 at the end of every year for the next 10 years (a total of 10 payments)."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Investment A pays $250 at the beginning of every year for the next 10 years (a total of 10 payments).",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 25,
                    "topic": "Various concepts",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A Treasury bond promises to pay a lump sum of $1,000 exactly 3 years from today. The nominal interest rate is 6%, semiannual compounding. Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The periodic interest rate is greater than 3%.",
                        "The periodic rate is less than 3%.",
                        "The present value would be greater if the lump sum were discounted back for more periods.",
                        "The present value of the $1,000 would be smaller if interest were compounded monthly rather than semiannually.",
                        "The PV of the $1,000 lump sum has a higher present value than the PV of a 3-year, $333.33 ordinary annuity."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The present value of the $1,000 would be smaller if interest were compounded monthly rather than semiannually.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 26,
                    "topic": "Various concepts",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is CORRECT, assuming positive interest rates and other things held constant?",
                    "options": [
                        "A 5-year, $250 annuity due will have a lower present value than a similar ordinary annuity.",
                        "A 30-year, $150,000 amortized mortgage will have larger monthly payments than an otherwise similar 20-year mortgage.",
                        "A typical investment's nominal interest rate will always be equal to or less than its effective annual rate.",
                        "If an investment pays 10% interest, compounded annually, its effective annual rate will be less than 10%.",
                        "Banks A and B offer the same nominal annual rate of interest, but A pays interest quarterly and B pays semiannually. Deposits in Bank B will have the higher future value if you leave the funds on deposit."
                    ],
                    "answer": "A typical investment's nominal interest rate will always be equal to or less than its effective annual rate.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 27,
                    "topic": "Various concepts",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The present value of a 3-year, $150 annuity due will exceed the present value of a 3-year, $150 ordinary annuity.",
                        "If a loan has a nominal annual rate of 8%, then the effective rate can never be less than 8%.",
                        "If a loan or investment has annual payments, then the effective, periodic, and nominal rates of interest will all be the same.",
                        "The proportion of the payment that goes toward interest on a fully amortized loan declines over time.",
                        "An investment that has a nominal rate of 6% with semiannual payments will have an effective rate that is less than 6%."
                    ],
                    "answer": "An investment that has a nominal rate of 6% with semiannual payments will have an effective rate that is less than 6%.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 28,
                    "topic": "Annuities",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are considering two equally risky annuities, each of which pays $5,000 per year for 10 years. Investment ORD is an ordinary (or deferred) annuity, while Investment DUE is an annuity due. Which of the following statements is CORRECT?",
                    "options": [
                        "The present value of ORD must exceed the present value of DUE, but the future value of ORD may be less than the future value of DUE.",
                        "The present value of DUE exceeds the present value of ORD, while the future value of DUE is less than the future value of ORD.",
                        "The present value of ORD exceeds the present value of DUE, and the future value of ORD also exceeds the future value of DUE.",
                        "The present value of DUE exceeds the present value of ORD, and the future value of DUE also exceeds the future value of ORD.",
                        "If the going rate of interest decreases, say from 10% to 0%, the difference between the present value of ORD and the present value of DUE would remain constant."
                    ],
                    "answer": "The present value of DUE exceeds the present value of ORD, and the future value of DUE also exceeds the future value of ORD.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 29,
                    "topic": "Effective annual rates",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You plan to invest some money in a bank account. Which of the following banks provides you with the highest effective rate of interest?",
                    "options": [
                        "Bank 1; 6.1% with annual compounding.",
                        "Bank 2; 6.0% with monthly compounding.",
                        "Bank 3; 6.0% with annual compounding.",
                        "Bank 4; 6.0% with quarterly compounding.",
                        "Bank 5; 6.0% with daily (365-day) compounding."
                    ],
                    "answer": "Bank 5; 6.0% with daily (365-day) compounding.",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 30,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What would the future value of $125 be after 8 years at 8.5% compound interest?",
                    "options": ["$205.83", "$216.67", "$228.07", "$240.08", "$252.08"],
                    "answer": "$240.08",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 31,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you have $1,500 and plan to purchase a 5-year certificate of deposit (CD) that pays 3.5% interest, compounded annually. How much will you have when the CD matures?",
                    "options": ["$1,781.53", "$1,870.61", "$1,964.14", "$2,062.34", "$2,165.46"],
                    "answer": "$1,781.53",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 32,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last year Toto Corporation's sales were $225 million. If sales grow at 6% per year, how large (in millions) will they be 5 years later?",
                    "options": ["$271.74", "$286.05", "$301.10", "$316.16", "$331.96"],
                    "answer": "$301.10",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 33,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How much would $1, growing at 3.5% per year, be worth after 75 years?",
                    "options": ["$12.54", "$13.20", "$13.86", "$14.55", "$15.28"],
                    "answer": "$13.20",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 34,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You deposit $1,000 today in a savings account that pays 3.5% interest, compounded annually. How much will your account be worth at the end of 25 years?",
                    "options": ["$2,245.08", "$2,363.24", "$2,481.41", "$2,605.48", "$2,735.75"],
                    "answer": "$2,363.24",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 35,
                    "topic": "PV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a U.S. government bond promises to pay $1,000 five years from now. If the going interest rate on 5-year government bonds is 5.5%, how much is the bond worth today?",
                    "options": ["$765.13", "$803.39", "$843.56", "$885.74", "$930.03"],
                    "answer": "$765.13",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 36,
                    "topic": "PV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How much would $5,000 due in 50 years be worth today if the discount rate were 7.5%?",
                    "options": ["$109.51", "$115.27", "$121.34", "$127.72", "$134.45"],
                    "answer": "$134.45",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 37,
                    "topic": "PV of a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a U.S. treasury bond will pay $2,500 five years from now. If the going interest rate on 5-year treasury bonds is 4.25%, how much is the bond worth today?",
                    "options": ["$1,928.78", "$2,030.30", "$2,131.81", "$2,238.40", "$2,350.32"],
                    "answer": "$2,030.30",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 38,
                    "topic": "Interest rate on a lump sum",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose the U.S. Treasury offers to sell you a bond for $747.25. No payments will be made until the bond matures 5 years from now, at which time it will be redeemed for $1,000. What interest rate would you earn if you bought this bond at the offer price?",
                    "options": ["4.37%", "4.86%", "5.40%", "6.00%", "6.60%"],
                    "answer": "6.00%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 39,
                    "topic": "Growth rate",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Ten years ago, Levin Inc. earned $0.50 per share. Its earnings this year were $2.20. What was the growth rate in Levin's earnings per share (EPS) over the 10-year period?",
                    "options": ["15.17%", "15.97%", "16.77%", "17.61%", "18.49%"],
                    "answer": "15.97%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 40,
                    "topic": "Number of periods",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "How many years would it take $50 to triple if it were invested in a bank that pays 3.8% per year?",
                    "options": ["23.99", "25.26", "26.58", "27.98", "29.46"],
                    "answer": "29.46",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 41,
                    "topic": "Number of periods",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Last year Mason Corp's earnings per share were $2.50, and its growth rate during the prior 5 years was 9.0% per year. If that growth rate were maintained, how many years would it take for Masons EPS to double?",
                    "options": ["5.86", "6.52", "7.24", "8.04", "8.85"],
                    "answer": "8.04",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 42,
                    "topic": "Number of periods",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You plan to invest in securities that pay 9.0%, compounded annually. If you invest $5,000 today, how many years will it take for your investment account to grow to $9,140.20?",
                    "options": ["4.59", "5.10", "5.67", "6.30", "7.00"],
                    "answer": "7.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 43,
                    "topic": "FV of an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You want to buy a new sports car 3 years from now, and you plan to save $4,200 per year, beginning one year from today. You will deposit your savings in an account that pays 5.2% interest. How much will you have just after you make the 3rd deposit, 3 years from now?",
                    "options": ["$11,973.07", "$12,603.23", "$13,266.56", "$13,929.88", "$14,626.38"],
                    "answer": "$13,266.56",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 44,
                    "topic": "FV of an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You want to go to Europe 5 years from now, and you can save $3,100 per year, beginning one year from today. You plan to deposit the funds in a mutual fund which you expect to return 8.5% per year. Under these conditions, how much will you have just after you make the 5th deposit, 5 years from now?",
                    "options": ["$18,368.66", "$19,287.09", "$20,251.44", "$21,264.02", "$22,327.22"],
                    "answer": "$18,368.66",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 45,
                    "topic": "FV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You want to buy a new sports car 3 years from now, and you plan to save $4,200 per year, beginning immediately. You will make 3 deposits in an account that pays 5.2% interest. Under these assumptions, how much will you have 3 years from today?",
                    "options": ["$13,956.42", "$14,654.24", "$15,386.95", "$16,156.30", "$16,964.11"],
                    "answer": "$13,956.42",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 46,
                    "topic": "FV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You want to go to Europe 5 years from now, and you can save $3,100 per year, beginning immediately. You plan to deposit the funds in a mutual fund which you expect to return 8.5% per year. Under these conditions, how much will you have just after you make the 5th deposit, 5 years from now?",
                    "options": ["$17,986.82", "$18,933.49", "$19,929.99", "$20,926.49", "$21,972.82"],
                    "answer": "$19,929.99",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 47,
                    "topic": "PV of an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What is the PV of an ordinary annuity with 10 payments of $2,700 if the appropriate interest rate is 6.5%?",
                    "options": ["$15,809.44", "$16,641.51", "$17,517.38", "$18,439.35", "$19,409.84"],
                    "answer": "$19,409.84",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 48,
                    "topic": "PV of an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You have a chance to buy an annuity that pays $1,200 at the end of each year for 3 years. You could earn 5.5% on your money in other investments with equal risk. What is the most you should pay for the annuity?",
                    "options": ["$2,636.98", "$2,775.77", "$2,921.86", "$3,075.64", "$3,237.52"],
                    "answer": "$3,237.52",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 49,
                    "topic": "PV of an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your aunt is about to retire, and she wants to buy an annuity that will supplement her income by $65,000 per year for 25 years, beginning a year from today. The going rate on such annuities is 6.25%. How much would it cost her to buy such an annuity today?",
                    "options": ["$770,963.15", "$811,540.16", "$852,117.17", "$894,723.02", "$939,459.18"],
                    "answer": "$811,540.16",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 50,
                    "topic": "PV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What is the PV of an annuity due with 10 payments of $2,700 at an interest rate of 6.5%?",
                    "options": ["$20,671.48", "$21,705.06", "$22,790.31", "$23,929.82", "$25,126.31"],
                    "answer": "$20,671.48",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 51,
                    "topic": "PV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You have a chance to buy an annuity that pays $550 at the beginning of each year for 3 years. You could earn 5.5% on your money in other investments with equal risk. What is the most you should pay for the annuity?",
                    "options": ["$1,412.84", "$1,487.20", "$1,565.48", "$1,643.75", "$1,725.94"],
                    "answer": "$1,565.48",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 52,
                    "topic": "PV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your aunt is about to retire, and she wants to buy an annuity that will provide her with $65,000 of income a year for 25 years, with the first payment coming immediately. The going rate on such annuities is 6.25%. How much would it cost her to buy the annuity today?",
                    "options": ["$739,281.38", "$778,190.93", "$819,148.35", "$862,261.42", "$905,374.49"],
                    "answer": "$862,261.42",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 53,
                    "topic": "PV of an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You own an oil well that will pay you $30,000 per year for 10 years, with the first payment being made today. If you think a fair return on the well is 8.5%, how much should you ask for if you decide to sell it?",
                    "options": ["$202,893", "$213,572", "$224,250", "$235,463", "$247,236"],
                    "answer": "$213,572",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 54,
                    "topic": "PV of an ordinary annuity plus an ending payment",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the present value of a 4-year ordinary annuity of $2,250 per year plus an additional $3,000 at the end of Year 4 if the interest rate is 5%?",
                    "options": ["$8,508.74", "$8,956.56", "$9,427.96", "$9,924.17", "$10,446.50"],
                    "answer": "$10,446.50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 55,
                    "topic": "Payments on an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you inherited $275,000 and invested it at 8.25% per year. How much could you withdraw at the end of each of the next 20 years?",
                    "options": ["$28,532.45", "$29,959.08", "$31,457.03", "$33,029.88", "$34,681.37"],
                    "answer": "$28,532.45",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 56,
                    "topic": "Payments on an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $375,000 and wants to retire. He expects to live for another 25 years, and to be able to earn 7.5% on his invested funds. How much could he withdraw at the end of each of the next 25 years and end up with zero in the account?",
                    "options": ["$28,843.38", "$30,361.46", "$31,959.43", "$33,641.50", "$35,323.58"],
                    "answer": "$33,641.50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 57,
                    "topic": "Payments on an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $375,000 and wants to retire. He expects to live for another 25 years, and he also expects to earn 7.5% on his invested funds. How much could he withdraw at the beginning of each of the next 25 years and end up with zero in the account?",
                    "options": ["$28,243.21", "$29,729.70", "$31,294.42", "$32,859.14", "$34,502.10"],
                    "answer": "$31,294.42",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 58,
                    "topic": "Payments on an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you inherited $275,000 and invested it at 8.25% per year. How much could you withdraw at the beginning of each of the next 20 years?",
                    "options": ["$22,598.63", "$23,788.03", "$25,040.03", "$26,357.92", "$27,675.82"],
                    "answer": "$26,357.92",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 59,
                    "topic": "Years to deplete an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $375,000 invested at 7.5%, and he now wants to retire. He wants to withdraw $35,000 at the end of each year, beginning at the end of this year. How many years will it take to exhaust his funds, i.e., run the account down to zero?",
                    "options": ["22.50", "23.63", "24.81", "26.05", "27.35"],
                    "answer": "22.50",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 60,
                    "topic": "Years to deplete an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $500,000 invested at 7.5%, and he now wants to retire. He wants to withdraw $40,000 at the beginning of each year, beginning immediately. How many years will it take to exhaust his funds, i.e., run the account down to zero?",
                    "options": ["23.16", "24.38", "25.66", "27.01", "28.44"],
                    "answer": "28.44",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 61,
                    "topic": "Interest rate implicit in an annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You just won the state lottery, and you have a choice between receiving $3,500,000 today or a 10-year annuity of $500,000, with the first payment coming one year from today. What rate of return is built into the annuity?",
                    "options": ["6.72%", "7.07%", "7.43%", "7.80%", "8.19%"],
                    "answer": "7.07%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 62,
                    "topic": "Interest rate implicit in an annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your girlfriend just won the Florida lottery. She has the choice of $15,000,000 today or a 20-year annuity of $1,050,000, with the first payment coming one year from today. What rate of return is built into the annuity?",
                    "options": ["2.79%", "3.10%", "3.44%", "3.79%", "4.17%"],
                    "answer": "3.44%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 63,
                    "topic": "Interest rate implicit in an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Assume that you own an annuity that will pay you $15,000 per year for 12 years, with the first payment being made today. Your uncle offers to give you $120,000 for the annuity. If you sell it, what rate of return would your uncle earn on his investment?",
                    "options": ["6.85%", "7.21%", "7.59%", "7.99%", "8.41%"],
                    "answer": "8.41%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 64,
                    "topic": "PV of a perpetuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the present value of a perpetuity that pays $250 per year if the appropriate interest rate is 5%?",
                    "options": ["$4,750.00", "$5,000.00", "$5,250.00", "$5,512.50", "$5,788.13"],
                    "answer": "$5,000.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 65,
                    "topic": "Rate of return on a perpetuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the rate of return you would earn if you paid $950 for a perpetuity that pays $85 per year?",
                    "options": ["6.52%", "7.25%", "8.05%", "8.95%", "9.84%"],
                    "answer": "8.95%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 66,
                    "topic": "PV of an uneven cash flow stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At a rate of 6.25%, what is the present value of the following cash flow stream? $0 at Time 0; $75 at the end of Year 1; $225 at the end of Year 2; $0 at the end of Year 3; and $300 at the end of Year 4?",
                    "options": ["$411.57", "$433.23", "$456.03", "$480.03", "$505.30"],
                    "answer": "$505.30",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 67,
                    "topic": "PV of an uneven cash flow stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What is the present value of the following cash flow stream at an interest rate of 12.0% per year? $0 at Time 0; $1,500 at the end of Year 1; $3,000 at the end of Year 2; $4,500 at the end of Year 3; and $6,000 at the end of Year 4.",
                    "options": ["$9,699.16", "$10,209.64", "$10,746.99", "$11,284.34", "$11,848.55"],
                    "answer": "$10,746.99",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 68,
                    "topic": "PV of an uneven cash flow stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An investment promises the following cash flow stream: $750 at Time 0; $2,450 at the end of Year 1 (or at t = 1); $3,175 at the end of Year 2; and $4,400 at the end of Year 3. At a discount rate of 8.0%, what is the present value of the cash flow stream?",
                    "options": ["$7,916.51", "$8,333.17", "$8,771.76", "$9,233.43", "$9,695.10"],
                    "answer": "$9,233.43",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 69,
                    "topic": "PV of an uneven cash flow stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What is the present value of the following cash flow stream if the interest rate is 6.0% per year? 0 at Time 0; $1,000 at the end of Year 1; and $2,000 at the end of Years 2, 3, and 4.",
                    "options": ["$5,986.81", "$6,286.16", "$6,600.46", "$6,930.49", "$7,277.01"],
                    "answer": "$5,986.81",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 70,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum, semiannual compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the future value of $1,500 after 5 years if the appropriate interest rate is 6%, compounded semiannually?",
                    "options": ["$1,819.33", "$1,915.08", "$2,015.87", "$2,116.67", "$2,222.50"],
                    "answer": "$2,015.87",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 71,
                    "topic": "PV of a lump sum, semiannual compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the present value of $1,500 discounted back 5 years if the appropriate interest rate is 6%, compounded semiannually?",
                    "options": ["$956.95", "$1,007.32", "$1,060.33", "$1,116.14", "$1,171.95"],
                    "answer": "$1,116.14",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 72,
                    "topic": "Years to deplete an ordinary annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $300,000 invested at 7.5%, and he now wants to retire. He wants to withdraw $35,000 at the end of each year, beginning at the end of this year. He also wants to have $25,000 left to give you when he ceases to withdraw funds from the account. For how many years can he make the $35,000 withdrawals and still have $25,000 left in the end?",
                    "options": ["14.21", "14.96", "15.71", "16.49", "17.32"],
                    "answer": "14.96",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 73,
                    "topic": "Years to deplete an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your uncle has $300,000 invested at 7.5%, and he now wants to retire. He wants to withdraw $35,000 at the beginning of each year, beginning immediately. He also wants to have $25,000 left to give you when he ceases to withdraw funds from the account. For how many years can he make the $35,000 withdrawals and still have $25,000 left in the end?",
                    "options": ["11.98", "12.61", "13.27", "13.94", "14.63"],
                    "answer": "13.27",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 74,
                    "topic": "Interest rate implicit in an annuity due",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You agree to make 24 deposits of $500 at the beginning of each month into a bank account. At the end of the 24th month, you will have $13,000 in your account. If the bank compounds interest monthly, what nominal annual interest rate will you be earning?",
                    "options": ["7.62%", "8.00%", "8.40%", "8.82%", "9.26%"],
                    "answer": "7.62%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 75,
                    "topic": "Payments on a perpetuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "What annual payment would you have to receive in order to earn a 7.5% rate of return on a perpetuity that has a cost of $1,250?",
                    "options": ["$89.06", "$93.75", "$98.44", "$103.36", "$108.53"],
                    "answer": "$93.75",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 76,
                    "topic": "FV of an uneven cash flow stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "At a rate of 6.5%, what is the future value of the following cash flow stream? $0 at Time 0; $75 at the end of Year 1; $225 at the end of Year 2; $0 at the end of Year 3; and $300 at the end of Year 4?",
                    "options": ["$526.01", "$553.69", "$582.83", "$613.51", "$645.80"],
                    "answer": "$645.80",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 77,
                    "topic": "Interest rate built into uneven CF stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An investment costs $1,000 (CF at t = 0) and is expected to produce cash flows of $75 at the end of each of the next 5 years, then an additional lump sum payment of $1,000 at the end of the 5th year. What is the expected rate of return on this investment?",
                    "options": ["6.77%", "7.13%", "7.50%", "7.88%", "8.27%"],
                    "answer": "7.50%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 78,
                    "topic": "Interest rate built into uneven CF stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "An investment costs $725 and is expected to produce cash flows of $75 at the end of Year 1, $100 at the end of Year 2, $85 at the end of Year 3, and $625 at the end of Year 4. What rate of return would you earn if you bought this investment?",
                    "options": ["4.93%", "5.19%", "5.46%", "5.75%", "6.05%"],
                    "answer": "6.05%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 79,
                    "topic": "FV of a lump sum, monthly compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the future value of $1,500 after 5 years if the appropriate interest rate is 6%, compounded monthly?",
                    "options": ["$1,922.11", "$2,023.28", "$2,124.44", "$2,230.66", "$2,342.19"],
                    "answer": "$2,023.28",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 80,
                    "topic": "PV of a lump sum, monthly compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Whats the present value of $1,525 discounted back 5 years if the appropriate interest rate is 6%, compounded monthly?",
                    "options": ["$969.34", "$1,020.36", "$1,074.06", "$1,130.59", "$1,187.12"],
                    "answer": "$1,130.59",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 81,
                    "topic": "APR vs. EAR",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Credit card issuers must by law print the Annual Percentage Rate (APR) on their monthly statements. If the APR is stated to be 18.00%, with interest paid monthly, what is the card's EFF%?",
                    "options": ["18.58%", "19.56%", "20.54%", "21.57%", "22.65%"],
                    "answer": "19.56%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 82,
                    "topic": "Comparing the effective cost of two bank loans",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "East Coast Bank offers to lend you $25,000 at a nominal rate of 7.5%, compounded monthly. The loan (principal plus interest) must be repaid at the end of the year. Midwest Bank also offers to lend you the $25,000, but it will charge an annual rate of 8.3%, with no interest due until the end of the year. What is the difference in the effective annual rates charged by the two banks?",
                    "options": ["0.93%", "0.77%", "0.64%", "0.54%", "0.43%"],
                    "answer": "0.54%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 83,
                    "topic": "Nominal rate vs. EFF%",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a bank offers to lend you $10,000 for one year at a nominal annual rate of 10.25%, but you must make interest payments at the end of each quarter and then pay off the $10,000 principal amount at the end of the year. What is the effective annual rate on the loan?",
                    "options": ["6.99%", "7.76%", "8.63%", "9.59%", "10.65%"],
                    "answer": "10.65%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 84,
                    "topic": "Nominal rate vs. EFF%",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose a bank offers to lend you $10,000 for 1 year on a loan contract that calls for you to make interest payments of $250.00 at the end of each quarter and then pay off the principal amount at the end of the year. What is the effective annual rate on the loan?",
                    "options": ["8.46%", "8.90%", "9.37%", "9.86%", "10.38%"],
                    "answer": "10.38%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 85,
                    "topic": "Nominal rate vs. EAR",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "If a bank pays a 4.50% nominal rate, with monthly compounding on deposits, what effective annual rate (EFF%) does the bank pay?",
                    "options": ["3.01%", "3.35%", "3.72%", "4.13%", "4.59%"],
                    "answer": "4.59%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 86,
                    "topic": "Nominal rate vs. EAR",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose your credit card issuer states that it charges a 15.00% nominal annual rate. If you must make monthly payments, which amounts to monthly compounding, what is the effective annual rate?",
                    "options": ["15.27%", "16.08%", "16.88%", "17.72%", "18.61%"],
                    "answer": "16.08%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 87,
                    "topic": "Interest charges, simple interest",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Pace Co. borrowed $25,000 at a rate of 7.25%, simple interest, with interest paid at the end of each month. The bank uses a 360-day year. How much interest would Pace have to pay in a 30-day month?",
                    "options": ["$136.32", "$143.49", "$151.04", "$158.59", "$166.52"],
                    "answer": "$151.04",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 88,
                    "topic": "Fractional time periods",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you deposited $5,000 in a bank account that pays 5.25% with daily compounding and a 360-day year. How much could you withdraw after 8 months, assuming each month has 30 days?",
                    "options": ["$5,178.09", "$5,436.99", "$5,708.84", "$5,994.28", "$6,294.00"],
                    "answer": "$5,178.09",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 89,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: payment",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you borrowed $12,000 at a rate of 9% and must repay it in 4 equal installments at the end of each of the next 4 years. How large would your payments be?",
                    "options": ["$3,704.02", "$3,889.23", "$4,083.69", "$4,287.87", "$4,502.26"],
                    "answer": "$3,704.02",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 90,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: payment",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you are buying your first house for $210,000, and are making a $20,000 down payment. You have arranged to finance the remaining amount with a 30-year, monthly payment, amortized mortgage at a 6.5% nominal interest rate. What will your equal monthly payments be?",
                    "options": ["$1,083.84", "$1,140.88", "$1,200.93", "$1,260.98", "$1,324.02"],
                    "answer": "$1,200.93",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 91,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: interest",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you borrowed $12,000 at a rate of 9% and must repay it in 4 equal installments at the end of each of the next 4 years. How much interest would you have to pay in the first year?",
                    "options": ["$925.97", "$974.70", "$1,026.00", "$1,080.00", "$1,134.00"],
                    "answer": "$1,080.00",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 92,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: interest",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You plan to borrow $30,000 at a 7% annual interest rate. The terms require you to amortize the loan with 6 equal end-of-year payments. How much interest would you be paying in Year 2?",
                    "options": ["$1,548.79", "$1,630.30", "$1,716.11", "$1,806.43", "$1,896.75"],
                    "answer": "$1,806.43",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 93,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: interest",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You plan to borrow $75,000 at a 7% annual interest rate. The terms require you to amortize the loan with 10 equal end-of-year payments. How much interest would you be paying in Year 2?",
                    "options": ["$4,395.19", "$4,626.52", "$4,870.02", "$5,113.52", "$5,369.19"],
                    "answer": "$4,870.02",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 94,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: payment",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you take out a $10,000 loan at a 6% nominal annual rate. The terms of the loan require you to make 12 equal end-of-month payments each year for 4 years, and then an additional final (balloon) payment of $4,000 at the end of the last month. What will your equal monthly payments be?",
                    "options": ["$131.06", "$137.96", "$145.22", "$152.86", "$160.91"],
                    "answer": "$160.91",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 95,
                    "topic": "Growing annuity: calculating the real rate",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You plan to make annual deposits into a bank account that pays a 5.00% nominal annual rate. You think inflation will amount to 2.50% per year. What is the expected annual real rate at which your money will grow?",
                    "options": ["1.98%", "2.20%", "2.44%", "2.68%", "2.95%"],
                    "answer": "2.44%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 96,
                    "topic": "Growing annuity due: withdraw constant real amt",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your father now has $1,000,000 invested in an account that pays 9.00%. He expects inflation to average 3%, and he wants to make annual constant dollar (real) beginning-of-year withdrawals over each of the next 20 years and end up with a zero balance after the 20th year. How large will his initial withdrawal (and thus constant dollar (real) withdrawals) be?",
                    "options": ["$66,154.58", "$69,636.40", "$73,301.47", "$77,159.45", "$81,220.47"],
                    "answer": "$81,220.47",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 97,
                    "topic": "Annuity due, N, monthly compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are considering investing in a Third World bank account that pays a nominal annual rate of 18%, compounded monthly. If you invest $5,000 at the beginning of each month, how many months will it take for your account to grow to $250,000? Round fractional years up.",
                    "options": ["23", "27", "32", "38", "44"],
                    "answer": "38",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 98,
                    "topic": "Annuity, N, monthly compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are considering investing in a bank account that pays a nominal annual rate of 6%, compounded monthly. If you invest $5,000 at the end of each month, how many months will it take for your account to grow to $200,000? Round fractional years up.",
                    "options": ["33", "37", "41", "45", "49"],
                    "answer": "37",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 99,
                    "topic": "Int rate, annuity, mos compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your childs orthodontist offers you two alternative payment plans. The first plan requires a $4,000 immediate up-front payment. The second plan requires you to make monthly payments of $137.41, payable at the end of each month for 3 years. What nominal annual interest rate is built into the monthly payment plan?",
                    "options": ["12.31%", "12.96%", "13.64%", "14.36%", "15.08%"],
                    "answer": "14.36%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 100,
                    "topic": "N, lifetime vs. annual pmts",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your subscription to Investing Wisely Weekly is about to expire. You plan to subscribe to the magazine for the rest of your life, and you can renew it by paying $75 annually, beginning immediately, or you can get a lifetime subscription for $750, also payable immediately. Assuming you can earn 5.5% on your funds and the annual renewal rate will remain constant, how many years must you live to make the lifetime subscription the better buy? Round fractional years up. (Hint: Be sure to remember that you are solving for how many years you must live, not for how many payments must be made.)",
                    "options": ["7", "8", "9", "11", "13"],
                    "answer": "13",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 101,
                    "topic": "Non-annual compounding",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You just deposited $2,500 in a bank account that pays a 12% nominal interest rate, compounded quarterly. If you also add another $5,000 to the account one year (12 months) from now and another $7,500 to the account two years from now, how much will be in the account three years (12 quarters) from now?",
                    "options": ["$17,422.59", "$18,339.57", "$19,256.55", "$20,219.37", "$21,230.34"],
                    "answer": "$18,339.57",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 102,
                    "topic": "Compare effective cost of two bank loans",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Merchants Bank offers to lend you $30,000 at a nominal rate of 6.0%, simple interest, with interest paid quarterly. Gold Coast Bank offers to lend you the $30,000, but it will charge 7.0%, simple interest, with interest paid at the end of the year. What's the difference in the effective annual rates charged by the two banks?",
                    "options": ["1.49%", "1.24%", "1.04%", "0.86%", "0.69%"],
                    "answer": "0.86%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 103,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: principal repayment",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you borrowed $12,000 at a rate of 9% and must repay it in 4 equal installments at the end of each of the next 4 years. By how much would you reduce the amount you owe in the first year?",
                    "options": ["$2,492.82", "$2,624.02", "$2,755.23", "$2,892.99", "$3,037.64"],
                    "answer": "$2,624.02",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 104,
                    "topic": "Loan amortization: ending balance",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Suppose you borrowed $12,000 at a rate of 9% and must repay it in 4 equal installments at the end of each of the next 4 years. How much would you still owe at the end of the first year, after you have made the first payment?",
                    "options": ["$7,636.79", "$8,038.73", "$8,461.82", "$8,907.18", "$9,375.98"],
                    "answer": "$9,375.98",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 105,
                    "topic": "Retirement planning",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your sister turned 35 today, and she is planning to save $5,000 per year for retirement, with the first deposit to be made one year from today. She will invest in a mutual fund that will provide a return of 8% per year. She plans to retire 30 years from today, when she turns 65, and she expects to live for 25 years after retirement, to age 90. Under these assumptions, how much can she spend in each year after she retires? Her first withdrawal will be made at the end of her first retirement year.",
                    "options": ["$47,888", "$50,408", "$53,061", "$55,714", "$58,500"],
                    "answer": "$53,061",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 106,
                    "topic": "Loan amort: int rate, % of pmt toward principal",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your company has just taken out a 1-year installment loan for $72,500. The nominal rate is 12.0%, but with equal end-of-month payments. What percentage of the 2nd monthly payment will go toward the repayment of principal?",
                    "options": ["73.01%", "76.85%", "80.89%", "85.15%", "89.63%"],
                    "answer": "89.63%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 107,
                    "topic": "Loan amort: pmt and % of pmt toward interest",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "A homeowner just obtained a 30-year amortized mortgage loan for $150,000 at a nominal annual rate of 6.5%, with 360 end-of-month payments. What percentage of the total payments made during the first 3 months will go toward payment of interest?",
                    "options": ["81.34%", "85.62%", "89.90%", "94.40%", "99.12%"],
                    "answer": "85.62%",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 108,
                    "topic": "Growing annuity: withdrawing constant real amt",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Your father now has $1,000,000 invested in an account that pays 9.00%. He expects inflation to average 3%, and he wants to make annual constant dollar (real) end-of-year withdrawals over each of the next 20 years and end up with a zero balance after the 20th year. How large will his initial withdrawal (and thus constant dollar (real) withdrawals) be?",
                    "options": ["$68,139.22", "$71,725.49", "$75,500.52", "$79,474.23", "$83,657.08"],
                    "answer": "$83,657.08",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 109,
                    "topic": "Growing annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You anticipate that you will need $1,500,000 when you retire 30 years from now. You plan to make 30 deposits, beginning today, in a bank account that will pay 6% interest, compounded annually. You expect to receive annual raises of 4%, so you will increase the amount you deposit each year by 4%. (That is, your 2nd deposit will be 4% greater than your first, the 3rd will be 4% greater than the 2nd, etc.) How much must your 1st deposit be if you are to meet your goal?",
                    "options": ["$10,216.60", "$10,754.31", "$11,320.33", "$11,886.35", "$12,480.66"],
                    "answer": "$11,320.33",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 110,
                    "topic": "Growing annuity",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You want to accumulate $2,500,000 in your 401(k) plan by your retirement date, which is 35 years from now. You will make 30 deposits into your plan, with the first deposit occurring today. The plan's rate of return typically averages 9%. You expect to increase each deposit by 2% as your income grows with inflation. (That is, your 2nd deposit will be 2% greater than your first, the 3rd will be 2% greater than the 2nd, etc.) How much must your 1st deposit at t = 0 be to enable you to meet your goal?",
                    "options": ["$8,718.90", "$9,154.84", "$9,612.58", "$10,093.21", "$10,597.87"],
                    "answer": "$8,718.90",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 111,
                    "topic": "Retirement planning",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "Steve and Ed are cousins who were both born on the same day. Both turned 25 today. Their grandfather began putting $2,500 per year into a trust fund for Steve on his 20th birthday, and he just made a 6th payment into the fund. The grandfather (or his estate's trustee) will continue with these $2,500 payments until a 46th and final payment is made on Steve's 65th birthday. The grandfather set things up this way because he wants Steve to work, not to be a 'trust fund baby,' but he also wants to ensure that Steve is provided for in his old age. Until now, the grandfather has been disappointed with Ed, hence has not given him anything. However, they recently reconciled, and the grandfather decided to make an equivalent provision for Ed. He will make the first payment to a trust for Ed later today, and he has instructed his trustee to make additional equal annual payments each year until Ed turns 65, when the 41st and final payment will be made. If both trusts earn an annual return of 8%, how much must the grandfather put into Ed's trust today and each subsequent year to enable him to have the same retirement nest egg as Steve after the last payment is made on their 65th birthday?",
                    "options": ["$3,726", "$3,912", "$4,107", "$4,313", "$4,528"],
                    "answer": "$3,726",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 112,
                    "topic": "FV of uneven CF stream",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "After graduation, you plan to work for Dynamo Corporation for 12 years and then start your own business. You expect to save and deposit $7,500 a year for the first 6 years and $15,000 annually for the following 6 years, with the first deposit being made a year from today. In addition, your grandfather just gave you a $25,000 graduation gift which you will deposit immediately. If the account earns 9% compounded annually, how much will you have when you start your business 12 years from now?",
                    "options": ["$238,176", "$250,712", "$263,907", "$277,797", "$291,687"],
                    "answer": "$277,797",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 113,
                    "topic": "Find CF for given return",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "You are negotiating to make a 7-year loan of $25,000 to Breck Inc. To repay you, Breck will pay $2,500 at the end of Year 1, $5,000 at the end of Year 2, and $7,500 at the end of Year 3, plus a fixed but currently unspecified cash flow, X, at the end of Years 4 through 7. Breck is essentially riskless, so you are confident the payments will be made, and you regard 8% as an appropriate rate of return on low risk 7-year loans. What cash flow must the investment provide at the end of each of the final 4 years, that is, what is X?",
                    "options": ["$4,271.67", "$4,496.49", "$4,733.15", "$4,969.81", "$5,218.30"],
                    "answer": "$4,733.15",
                    "explanation": ""
                },
                {
                    "q_num": 114,
                    "topic": "Saving for college",
                    "type": "mcq",
                    "question": "John and Daphne are saving for their daughter Ellen's college education. Ellen is now 10 years old and will be entering college 8 years from now (t = 8). College tuition and expenses at State U. are currently $14,500 a year, but they are expected to increase at a rate of 3.5% a year. They expect Ellen to graduate in 4 years. (If Ellen wants to go to graduate school, she will be on her own.) Tuition and other costs will be due at the beginning of each school year (at t = 8, 9, 10, and 11). So far, John and Daphne have accumulated $15,000 in the college savings account. Their long-run financial plan is to add an additional $5,000 at the beginning of each of the next 4 years (at t = 0, 1, 2, and 3). Then they plan to make 4 equal annual contributions at the end of each of the following 5 years (t = 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8). They expect their investment account to earn 9%. How large must the annual payments be at t = 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8 to meet Ellen's anticipated college costs?",
                    "options": ["$777.96", "$818.91", "$862.01", "$907.38", "$955.13"],
                    "answer": "$955.13",
                    "explanation": ""
                }
            ]
        }
    }
}
